seemed almost indifferent as to the effect he produced.
At this, Snowball sprang to his feet and shouting down the sheep, who had begun
bleating again, broke into a passionate appeal in favor of the windmill.
Until now, the animals had been about equally divided in their sympathies, but
in a moment Snowball's eloquence had carried them away.
In glowing sentences, he painted a picture of Animal Farm as it might be
when sordid labor was lifted from the animals' backs.
His imagination had now run far beyond chaff cutters and turnip slicers.
"Electricity," he said, "could operate threshing machines, plows, harrows,
rollers, and reapers and binders, besides supplying every stall with its
own electric light, hot and cold water, and an electric heater."
By the time he had finished speaking, there was no doubt as to which way the
vote would go.
But just at this moment, Napoleon stood up, and casting a peculiar sidelong look
at Snowball, uttered a high-pitched whimper of a kind no one had ever heard him utter before.
At this, there was a terrible baying sound outside, and nine enormous dogs,
wearing brass-studded collars, came bounding into the barn.
They dashed straight for Snowball, who only sprang from his place just in time
to escape their snapping jaws.
In a moment, he was out of the door, and they were after him.
Too amazed and frightened to speak, all the animals crowded through the door to watch the chase.
Snowball was racing across the long pasture that led to the road.
He was running as only a pig can run, but the dogs were close on his heels.
Suddenly, he slipped, and it seemed certain that they had him.
Then he was up again, running faster than ever.
Then the dogs were gaining on him again.
One of them all but closed his jaws on Snowball's tail, but Snowball whisked it
free just [music] in time.
Then he put on an extra spurt, and with a few inches to spare, slipped through a
hole in the hedge, and was seen no more.
Silent and terrified, the animals crept back into the barn.
In a moment, the dogs came bounding back.
At first, no one had been able to imagine where these creatures came from,
but the problem was soon solved.
They were the puppies whom Napoleon had taken away from their mothers and reared privately.
Though not yet full-grown, they were huge dogs and as fierce-looking as wolves.
They kept close to Napoleon.
It was noticed that they wagged their tails to him in the same way as the
other dogs had been used to do to Mr.
Jones.
Napoleon, with the dogs following him, now mounted onto the raised portion of
the floor where Major had previously stood to deliver his speech.
He announced that from now on, the Sunday morning meetings would come to an end.
"They were unnecessary," he said, "and wasted time."
In future, all questions relating to the working of the farm would be settled by
a special committee of pigs presided over by himself.
These would meet in private and afterwards communicate their decisions to the others.
The animals would still assemble on Sunday mornings to salute the flag, sing
Beasts of England, and receive their orders for the week, but there would be no more debates.
In spite of the shock that Snowball's expulsion had given them, the animals
were dismayed by this announcement.
Several of them would have protested if they could have found the right arguments.
Even Boxer was vaguely troubled.
He set his ears back, shook his forelock several times, and tried hard to marshal his thoughts.
But in the end, he could not think of anything to say.
Some of the pigs themselves, however, were more articulate.
Four young porkers in the front row uttered shrill squeals of disapproval,
and all four of them sprang to their feet and began speaking at once.
But, suddenly, the dogs sitting round Napoleon let out deep, menacing growls,
and the pigs fell silent and sat down again.
Then, the sheep broke out into a tremendous bleating of "Four legs good, two legs bad!"